# Phan Tien Long .NET Software Engineer

 tienlong291099@gmail.com

**\** 098 333 6103

Ho Chi Minh City

1999/06/30

github.com/longblue2910



## **SUMMARY**

I'm .NET Software Engineer with over 3+ years of experience in developing .NET applications.

I am seeking opportunities to join a challenging environment that offers exciting projects utilizing .NET technology. My goal is to continuously enhance my skills and contribute to the development of breakthrough and efficient applications.

I also spend time learning new technologies and best practices to become a better engineer.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022/07 - present Ho Chi Minh City

### ISD Corp - Backend Engineer

- Ajinomoto Material Receive: Building a material receive system for AVN and integrate with SAP
  - Technologies: NET Core 8.0, Azure Cloud, MS SQL Server, React, React Native
  - Role: Backend Engineer
- DGW Warranty System: Building a warranty system for DGW and integrate with SAP
  - Technologies: NET Core 8.0, MS SQL Server, React, React Native
  - Role: Backend Engineer
- ITP MES: Development operating system for the factory and integrate with Oracle NetSuite
  - Technologies: NET Core 6.0, MS SQL Server, React, React Native
  - Role: Backend Engineer
- An Cuong CRM: Development of a comprehensive CRM system for An Cuong and integrate with SAP
  - Technologies: NET Core 5.0, NET Framework 4.8, MS SQL Server, React, React Native
  - Role: Backend Engineer

#### \* Responsibilities:

- Define the architecture (incorporating both the CQRS and MediatR patterns, Autofac), coding convention
- Refactor, write unit test and documentation to help developers faster and easier.
- Design database schema and implement back-end services
- Develop API to connect with front-end, mobile dev or partner
- Deploy web application in Windows Server with IIS, Azure Cloud
- Build automated systems (sending mail, data synchronization, ...) designed with Hangfire and Windows Service.
- Develop integration functions with external systems such as Microsoft Graph, Zalo OA, ERP SAP, ERP NetSuite ,...

2021/03 - 2022/06 Hue City

# 3S Intersoft SJC - Backend Engineer

- EVN EX1: Develop a electrical service management software for EVN Hanoi.
  - Technologies: NET Core 5.0, React, Flutter
  - Role: Backend Engineer
- MMI MCS: Develop a part of Sales management system for healthy foods for MMI Japan
  - Technologies: .NET Framework MVC, ADO .NET, PostgreSQL
  - Role: Backend Engineer

- EVN KPI: Develop a software to synthesize the set of targets to implement the plan for EVN Hanoi.
  - Technologies: .NET Core 3.1, React, Flutter
  - Role: Backend Engineer

# \* Responsibilities:

- Develop back-end processing content according to project requirements
- Develop API to connect with front-end, mobile dev or partner
- Write unit test and clean code.
- Develop new function according to project requirements

2020/08 - 2021/01 Hue City Aureole Information Technology - Fresher Developer

#### **EDUCATION**

2017/08 - 2020/08 Hue City, Viet Nam Hue Science University

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

# **Programming Languagues:**

- C#, JavaScript.

# **Database Management Systems:**

- MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, NoSQL(MongoDb, Redis)

#### Frameworks/Platforms

- ASP .NET Core, ASP .NET Framework.
- Restful API, .NET MVC.
- Entity Framework, Dapper.
- Ling, Store Procedure.
- Unit Testing.
- Hangfire, Windows Service
- JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, SCSS.

#### Others:

- Understanding of OOP methodologies, SOLID principles and design patterns
- Experience with version control systems (e.g., Git) and Agile/Scrum development methodologies.

# **PASTIMES AND ACTIVITIES**

- I am keen on reading books, IT blogs in my free time. My favorite sport is fooball.
- In my free time, I also spend time learning new technologies and best practices, learn English